Guide to the Cornell University College of Engineering photographs, 1870-1965.
Cornell University College of Engineering photographs, 1870-1965
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University College of Engineering photographs, 1870-1965.
16-2-2378
Cornell University.College of Engineering.
.5 cubic ft.
Photographs, Maps, Portraits, Negatives, Contact Sheets
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
College of Engineering photographic negatives, ca. 1945-1965, unidentified; seven lantern slides of field trips, 1870-1900, identified; photographs of Physics Dept. apparatus, 1870s-1880s, identified; five glass negatives and photographs of the construction of the Hydraulic Laboratory; glass slides depicting College of Engineering equipment and facilities (1870-1900); and photographs of John McMullen with a McMullen Scholarship brochure.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
College of Engineering photographic negatives, ca. 1945-1965, unidentified; seven lantern slides of field trips, 1870-1900, identified; photographs of Physics Dept. apparatus, 1870s-1880s, identified; five glass negatives and photographs of the construction of the Hydraulic Laboratory; glass slides depicting College of Engineering equipment and facilities (1870-1900); and photographs of John McMullen with a McMullen Scholarship brochure.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; McMullen, John, 1848-1921.; Cornell University--Description--Views.
Subjects:
Physical instruments.; Engineering--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Negatives.; Photographs.; Lantern slides.; Negatives.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Faculty (multiple names in the folder(s) for each letter: A-P (Box 1)
- Faculty: Q/R-Z (Box 2)
- Faculty: Earlier photos, A-Z (Box 2)
- Faculty: Retired, A-Z (Box 2)
- Unidentified man (Portrait) (Box 3)
- W. L. Malcolm, Director of Civil Engineering, 1939-1946 (Box 3)
- John Rennie (old engraving) (Box 3)
- Faculty moved away (4 folders) (Box 3)
- Faculty deceased (Box 3)
- Scheele (Box 3)
- Streett (Box 3)
- Tang (Box 3)
- Wolga (Box 3)
- Unidentified students and faculty (Box 3)
- Cartes-de-visite (Box 3)
  Classes of: 1882-1884, 1886-1892, 1895-1897, 1899, 1901, 1902
- Army engineers (Rolled Print), 1917 (Box 3)
- 35th National Convention of Society for the Promotion of Engineering Education, University of Orono, Maine (Rolled Print), 1927 (Box 3)
- Departments
- Agricultural Engineering (Box 4)
- Applied Mathematics (Box 4)
- Applied Physics [Applied and Engineering Physics] (Box 4)
- Chemical Engineering (Box 4)
- Civil and Environmental Engineering (Box 4)
- Computer Science (Box 4)
- Electrical Engineering [Electrical and Computer Engineering] (Box 5)
- EE historical (Box 5)
- Geology/Geological Sciences (Box 5)
- Materials Science and Engineering (Box 5)
- Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering (Box 5)
- Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering (Box 6)
- Nuclear Engineering (Box 6)
- Operations Research [Industrial Engineering] (Box 6)
- Theoretical and Applied Mechanics (Box 6)
- Centers, Labs, and Programs
- Arecibo (Box 6)
- CADIF (Box 6)
- Center for Environmental Research (Box 6)
- CHESS (Cornell High Energy Synchrotron Source) (Box 6)
- COMEPP (Cornell Manufacturing, Engineering, and Productivity Program) (Box 6)
- Computing/ Computing Graphics (Box 6)
- Computers and Computing History (Box 6)
- De Frees Hydraulics Lab (Box 6)
- De Frees dedication (Box 6)
- Earthquakes and National Center for Earthquake Engineering Research (Box 6)
- Electronic Packaging Alliance (Box 6)
- Emerson Lab (Box 7)
- Engineering Communications (Box 7)
- Hamilton (Box 7)
- Joint Services and Electronics Program (Box 7)
- NNF (National Nanoscale Facility)/ Knight Lab (Box 7)
- NRRFSS (National Research and Resource Facility for Submicron Structures) (Box 7)
- Plasma Studies (LPS: Laboratory of Plasma Studies) (Box 7)
- Satellite (Box 7)
- SRC (Semiconductor Research Corporation Program in Microscience and Technology) (Box 7)
- Waste Management (CWMI and NYS SWCI) (Box 7)
- Buildings
- Album: Photos of construction of Cornell Hydraulic Laboratory, 1897-1898 (Box 7)
- Engineering buildings--Former (Box 7)
- Buildings--Aerial views (Box 7)
- Bard Hall (Box 7)
- Between classes (Box 7)
- Biotechnology (Box 7)
- Buildings--Interiors (Box 7)
- Buildings--Others (Box 7)
- Campus: Engineering (2 folders) (Box 7)
- Carpenter Hall (Box 7)
- Clark Hall (Box 7)
- Grumman Hall (Box 7)
- Hollister Hall (Box 7)
- Hollister Hall-oversized photo (Folder 1)
- ILR (Box 7)
- Kimball Hall (Box 7)
- Olin Hall--Interiors (Box 7)
- Phillips Hall (Box 7)
- Snee Hall (Box 7)
- Theory Center (Box 7)
- Thurston Hall (Box 7)
- Upson Hall (Box 7)
- Ward Lab (Box 7)
- Wilson Synchrotron (Box 7)
- Winter Laboratory (Box 7)
- Alphabetical By Subjects (Folder Titles Supplied By Engineering College)
- Academic Rush Week (Box 8)
- Admissions (Box 8)
- Admissions, 1986 (Box 8)
- Admissions, Advising, and Counselling (Box 8)
- Advising and Counselling (Box 8)
- AID (Box 8)
- Alumni (2 folders) (Box 8)
- Alumni Affairs (Box 8)
- Alumni Benefits (Box 8)
- Alumni Convocation (Box 8)
- Arbor Day--Paper Recycling (Box 8)
- Basic Studies (Box 8)
- Benefactors (Box 8)
- Blackboards (Box 8)
- Career Services (Box 8)
- China (Box 8)
- Classroom scenes (Box 8)
- Commencement (Box 8)
- Committees: College (Box 8)
- Contests (Box 8)
- Contests--Fun-type (Box 8)
- Continuing Education (Box 8)
- Convocation, 1971 (Box 8)
- CO-OP Program (2 folders) (Box 8)
- Cornell Engineer (Box 8)
- COSEP mini-course (Box 8)
- Danby Telescope (Box 9)
- Design Project (Box 9)
- Dictation (Box 9)
- Dogs (Box 9)
- EE Centennial (Box 9)
- Energy (Box 9)
- Energy lectures (Box 9)
- Engineering (Miscellanous Photos) (Box 9)
- Engineering, 1980 (Box 9)
- Engineering Award (Box 9)
- Engineering College Council (2 folders) (Box 9)
- Engineering College Staff (Box 9)
- Engineering Education Coalition (Box 9)
- Engineering Conference (Box 9)
- Engineering "Historical" (Box 9)
- Engineering Quarterly (Box 9)
- Engineer's Day (Box 9)
- Freshman Center (Box 9)
- Freshman Center, 1971 (Box 9)
- Frosh Orientation (Box 9)
- Hatfield Fellow, 1982 (Box 9)
- Historical (Box 9)
- Historical: Portraits (Box 9)
- Laboratory scenes (Box 9)
- Law and Environmental Control (Box 9)
- Lecture (Box 9)
- Libraries (Box 9)
- Lunar Rover (Box 9)
- Master of Engineering (Box 9)
- Master of Engineering, 1981 (Box 9)
- Master of Engineering Design projects (Box 9)
- Master Plan (Box 10)
- Materials Learning Center (Box 10)
- McManus, 1980 (Box 10)
- McMullen Scholarship (Box 10)
- Mini courses (Box 10)
- Minority Programs (Box 10)
- Moods (Box 10)
- Photogrammetry (Box 10)
- Placement (Box 10)
- Pollution--traffic (Box 10)
- Rawlings (Box 10)
- Registration (Box 10)
- Research Reviews (Box 10)
- Reunion (Box 10)
- Reunion, 1968 (Box 10)
- Scholarships (Box 10)
- Schultz (Box 10)
- Science photos (Box 10)
- Social Implications of Technology (Box 10)
- Special events (Box 10)
- Student Awards (Box 10)
- Students (Box 10)
- Students 1970 - Identified (multiple photos: in class; in the lab; on campus; in the dorms) (Box 10)
  - Roger K. Berman, EE, 1970
  - Carter
  - Gary Cokins, ORIE, 1972
  - George E. Gull, MAE, 1972
  - Robert E. Kingan, EE, 1969
  - Otis W. Sprow, Mech.E, 1970
  - Thomas M. Wozny, AEP, 1973
- Students(3 more folders; to be processed), 1970 (Box 10)
- Summer Jobs (Box 10)
- Superconductivity (Box 10)
- Tau Beta Pi (Box 10)
- Teaching Awards, 1995 (Box 10)
- Techniques of Engineering Education (Box 10)
- Telegraph (Box 10)
- Texture, Design, etc (Box 10)
- Transportation (Box 10)
- TV Classroom (Box 10)
- Twentieth Anniversary Program, [Applied & Engr. Physics], June 1966 (Box 10)
- Underground Research (Box 10)
- Urban (Box 10)
- VIP for General (notes), April 1982 (Box 10)
- Women in Engineering (Box 10)
- General Cornell Views--Non-Engineering
- Athletics (Box 11)
- Between classes (Box 11)
- Book Store (Box 11)
- Campus (Box 11)
- Campus Field & Stream (2 folders) (Box 11)
- Collegetown (Box 11)
- Community--Rural (Box 11)
- Community--Urban (Box 11)
- Constituent Assembly, 1969 (Box 11)
- Distant Views (Box 11)
- Dormitories (Box 11)
- Housing and Dining (Box 11)
- McGraw Tower (Box 11)
- Performing Arts (Box 11)
- Recreation/ Sports (Box 11)
- Statler (Box 11)
- Prints, Contact Sheets and Negatives (By Photographer or Photo Agency Name)
- Dede Hatch (Box 12)
- Doug Hicks (Box 12)
- C. Hadley Smith (Box 12)
- In-house photos (Box 12)
- University Photography, (Harrington) contact sheets, 1987-1989 (Box 12)
- University Photography, contact sheets, 1990-1997 (Box 12)
- Visual Services contact sheets (Box 12)
- Special negatives (Box 12)
- Others (Box 12)
- Box of unidentified old negatives (Box 12)
- David Ruether contact sheets and negatives
  [Note: Engineering College owns copyright to Ruether's images]
- Contact sheets (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, 1973 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, 1975 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, June 1975 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, November 1975 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, December 1975 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, 1976 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, Spring and Fall 1976 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, December 1976 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, May 1977 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, Spring 1977; 1983-1984 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
- Contact sheets, 1987-1989 (Box 13)
- Additional folders, undated (Box 13)
- Negatives: C-22, C-23, 25-36 (Box 13)
- Negatives: 37-54 (Box 13)
- Negatives: E73, E74, E77, E79, E81, Eng 109, Eng 114, Eng 117 (Box 14)
- Cornell 11, C-12, C14, C-16, C-19, 2nd Run, Cornell 20 (Box 14)
- Engineering buildings: contact sheets and negatives, July 1971 (Box 14)
- 83-E-1 through 85-E-43 (Box 14)
- 85-E-44 through 89-E-16 (Box 14)
- 90-E-1 through 91-E-15 (Box 14)
- Bridges, construction, railroads, tunnels (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, tunnels (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, railroads, tunnels (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, distribution gates, railroads (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, piers, tunnels (Box 15)
- Bridges, buildings, construction, railroads (Box 15)
- Bridges, buildings, canals, construction, dams, railroads, tunnels (Box 15)
- Bridges, buildings, construction, dams, railroads, reservoirs, tunnels (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, railroads, tunnels, water systems (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, power lines (Box 15)
- Bridges, rock tunneling machine (Box 15)
- Bridge, Africans, tunnels (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, tunnels (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, water works (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, wireless towers (Box 15)
- Bridges, buildings, construction (Box 15)
- Bridges, buildings, construction, streets (Box 15)
- Bridges, buildings, construction, railroads (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, railroads (Box 15)
- Concrete frame building, Portland, Maine (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, dams, piers, railroads, reactors, unidentified machinery (Box 15)
- Bridges, buildings, coffer dams, construction, viaducts (Box 15)
- Bridges, construction, horses and wagons hauling materials, piers, railroads (Box 15)
- Buildings, construction, pier (Box 15)
- Blasting, bridges, canals, construction, dams, foundations, machinery and plumbing, piers, respirators and testing laboratories (Box 16)
- Aqueducts, bridges, buildings, construction, dams drainage ditches, laying pipeline, machinery, tunnels, worker standing on his head atop span under construction (Box 16)
- Blasting, buildings, construction, machinery, piers (Box 16)
- Bridges, construction, drawbridges, foundations, railroads, test train (Box 16)
- Bridge collapse, bridges, construction, drawbridges, piers, railroads, sewer outlets, subways, tunnels (Box 16)
- Bridge conveyers, bridges, construction (Box 16)
- Sewage works school (C.U.), Michigan Community Health Project, Civil Engineering faculty (1956), bridges, construction (Box 16)
- Bridges, buildings, construction, disposal plant, pouring concrete (Box 16)
- Bridges, buildings, construction, machinery, piers, portraits of three early engineers (Box 16)
- Prints and negatives taken by Professors Walker and Hollister, reprint by D. L Frizzell (Box 16)
- Prints and negatives of bridges, construction, Africans (Box 16)
- Prints and negatives of bridges, buildings, construction, test train (Box 16)
- Bridges, construction, machinery, miscellany (Box 16)
- Bridges, construction, survey camp, miscellany (Box 16)
- Bridges (over-size prints) (Box 17)
- Civil Engineering (over-size prints) (Box 18)
  Annual banquet, bridges, canals, railroads
- Civil Engineering (over-size prints) (Box 19)
  Faculty and students group portraits, portrait of unidentified woman,bridges, canals, piers, railroads
- Civil Engineering (over-size prints) (Box 20)
  Bridges, construction
- Civil Engineering (over-size prints) (Box 21)
  Construction, bridges, buildings
- Civil Engineering (over-size prints): map (Box 22)
  "area covered by the first summer survey of the College of Engineering, Spring 1874" (in Canada; including partial views of the Canadian Pacific RR, the South Saskatchewan River, and several towns; not a field map, but drawn by a member of the class after the survey)
- Construction, bridges, buildings, railroads (Box 22)
- Civil Engineering (over-size prints) (Box 23)
  Aerial photos, construction, bridges, buildings, railroads
- Civil Engineering: bridges, buildings, construction, dams, piers, railroads (Box 24)
- Jon Reis contact sheets and negatives
- Negatives and contact sheets: Library Tower (Box 25)
- Contact sheets: Athletics (Box 25)
- Contact sheets: Museum and Library after 1966 (Box 25)
- Contact sheets: "campuses" (Box 25)
- Contact sheets: Mechanical Engineering (Box 25)
- Contact sheets: Engineering Campuses (Box 25)
- Negative: Inside front cover,"The Surface of a high-density sample of magnesium," photo by Dr. P. Morgan, 1966 (Box 25)
- Contact sheets (3 more folders) (Box 25)
- McManus luncheon, May 1980 (Box 25)
- Engineering Corp., February 1980 (Box 25)
- Ellie Moulton's retirement party, December 1980 (Box 25)
- Contact sheet, 1980-1986 (Box 25)
- Everhart retirement, July 1984 (Box 25)
- Contact sheet, 1981 (Box 25)
- Contact sheet, 1982 (Box 25)
- Contact sheet, 1983 (Box 25)
- Contact sheet, 1987 (Box 25)
- Contact sheet, 1989-1990 (Box 25)
- In map case: Bundle (oversize prints) (Box 25)
  Unidentified portrait, College de Genie Civil, Batiment Principal
- Additional material, housed in manuscript collection box. (Box 37, Folder m.16-2-2378)